A Guide to the Papers of John Dos Passos 1865-1998
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Correspondence
  - General correspondence with Dos Passos (Box 1-11)
    - Leeds, William B. 1964-1966, 5 items (Box 5)
      re: John Dos Passos's article on Hemingway
    - Leighton, Alexander H. 1947 (Box 5)
    - Leifermann, Hank n.d. (Box 5)
    - Leite, Tito 1958-1966, 7 items (Box 5)
    - Lévêque, Maurice 1919 (Box 5)
    - Leyer, F. n.d. (Box 5)
    - Lindsley, Lonia 1943 (Box 5)
    - Liza n.d. (Box 5)
    - Lorraine, G. B. 1945 (Box 5)
    - Loveman, Amy 1950 (Box 5)
      re: National Conference of Christians and Jews
    - Lowndes, Marion (Diddy) 1936-1970, n.d., 56 items (Box 5)
    - Lowndes, Lloyd and Marion (Diddy) 1925-1970, n.d., 53 items (Box 5)
    - Lucas-Championnière, Germaine ca. 1919-1968, n.d., 55 items (Box 6)
    - Luce, Clare Booth 1965 (Box 6)
    - Luce, Henry R. 1946 (Box 6)
    - Lyman, Vera I. 1929 (Box 6)
    - Lynch, Robert 1969 (Box 6)
    - Lyons, Lt. Cmdr. W. F. 1945 (Box 6)
    - McAdoo, Francis H. 1963 (Box 6)
    - McBride, Mr. 1947 (incomplete) (Box 6)
    - McBrown, Mr. 1962 (Box 6)
    - McCann, James 1932, 2 items (Box 6)
    - McComb, Arthur K. 1917-1967, n.d., 214 items, 4 folders (Box 6)
      with photo
    - McComb, Arthur K. 1916-1966, 38 items (Box 6)
    - McCooke, Carson T. 1965 (Box 7)
    - McCormick, Wright (Micky) 1917-1919, n.d., 24 items (Box 7)
    - McCormick, Wright (Micky) n.d. (Box 7)
    - MacLeish, Archibald and Ada 1935-1936, n.d., 12 items (Box 7)
    - Mann, Thomas 1947 (Box 7)
    - Maque n.d. (Box 7)
      with untitled poem
    - Marble, Henry C., M.D. 1947 (Box 7)
    - Margery 1905 [?] (Box 7)
    - Marianna 1917-1919, 2 items (Box 7)
    - Marquand, John P. 1947 (Box 7)
    - Marth [?] 1901 (Box 7)
    - Martin, James (Slim) 1939, 1955-1959, n.d., 13 items (Box 7)
    - Marvin, Walter Rumsey (Rummy) and Betsy 1915-1970,n.d., 60 items (Box 7)
    - Massey, Edward (Eddie) 1918-1920, n.d., 6 items (Box 7)
    - Mastenbrock, A., Jr. 1946, n.d., 2 items (Box 7)
    - Mathé, Juan J. 1962, 3 items (Box 7)
    - Maverick, Maury 1936 (Box 7)
    - "Me" 1928-1930, n.d., 5 items (Box 7)
      (photo)
    - Meakin, Miss Louisa (Auntie Lou) 1904-1934, n.d., 29 items (Box 7)
    - Mearns, David C. 1961 (Box 7)
    - Mearns, David C. 1962 (Box 7)
    - Medeiros, Paulina 1943 (Box 7)
    - Mencken, H. L. 1947, 2 items (Box 148)
    - Mihajlov, Marija 1966 (Box 7)
    - Mildred 1947 (Box 7)
    - Milhaud, Darius M. 1945 (Box 7)
    - Miller, F. Dewolfe 1961 (Box 7)
    - Miller, Henry n.d. (Box 148)
    - Miller, Walter 1947 (Box 7)
    - Milliken [?], L. A. 1952 (Box 7)
    - Mills et al 1936 (Box 7)
      re: Sophia Louise Meakin [Auntie Lou's] will
    - Mitchell, Stewart (Auk) 1916-1955, n.d., 26 items (Box 7)
    - Moca[?] 1936 (Box 8)
    - Moe, Henry Allen 1940, 1963, 2 items (Box 8)
    - Moholy, Lucia 1934 (Box 8)
    - Monet, Mademoiselle n.d. (Box 8)
    - Montet, M. 1903-1904, n.d., 6 items (Box 8)
    - Mooney, Tom 1936 (Box 8)
    - Morelock, Horace W. 1940 (Box 8)
    - Morison, Samuel Eliot 1964, 2 items (Box 8)
    - Mowrer [Hemingway], Hadley and Paul 1948 (Box 8)
    - Mumford, Lewis ca. 1936 (Box 8)
    - Muraro, Michelangelo 1954 (Box 8)
    - Murphy, Gerald and Sara 1925-1964, n.d., 163 items, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Murphy, Gerald and/or Sara 1935-1947, n.d., 35 items (Box 8)
      by Katy Dos Passos
    - Murphy, Wallace Smith n.d. (Box 8)
    - Nathan, Robert 1966 (Box 8)
    - Nelson, Frederic 1964, 2 items (Box 8)
    - The New Leader, Editor 1954 (Box 8)
    - New Republic, Editor 1930 (Box 8)
    - New World Settlement Fund, Inc. 1945, n.d. (Box 8)
    - New York Times Book Review Section, Editor 1947 (Box 8)
    - Nir, M. ou[?] 1941 (Box 8)
    - Nix, Ruul[?] 1927 (Box 8)
    - Nixon, Richard 1968 (Box 148)
    - Nock, Albert Jay 1920 (Box 8)
    - Norman and Susan 1931-1932, n.d., 4 items (Box 8)
    - Orr, Elaine 1921-1950, n.d., 6 items (Box 8)
    - Overholder, Winfred (M.D.) 1944 (Box 8)
      re: cousin, Ida L. Pifer
    - Owens, Hamilton and Olga 1965, n.d., 2 items (Box 8)
    - Padilla y de Barbon de Berretta Moreno, Isabel n.d. (Box 8)
    - Paycua, M.[?] 1937 (Box 8)
    - Pearson, Norman Holmes 1955 (Box 8)
    - Pegler, Westbrook 1958, n.d., 4 items (Box 8)
    - Peixoto, Ernani de Amaral 1958 (Box 8)
    - Perez, Ismael Diego n.d. (Box 8)
    - Peroutka, Ferinand 1960 (Box 8)
    - Perry, George 1943 (Box 8)
    - Pfeiffer, Karl 1943-1966, 3 items (Box 8)
    - Phillips, Howard S. 1932-1967, 3 items (Box 8)
    - Pietens, Mr. 1965 (Box 8)
    - Pinheiro, Israel 1960, 1968, 2 items (Box 8)
    - Poore, Dudley (Pobrecito) 1916-1970s, n.d., 91 items (2 folders) (Box 9)
      with photos
    - Poore, Dudley (Dudloysha) 1917, 4 items (Box 9)
    - Porter, Helen H. K. 1920, n.d., 3 items (Box 9)
    - Powell, Dawn ca. 1930s-1965, n.d., 37 items (Box 9)
    - Powell, Marcia Llewlly and John A. 1954-1970, 5 items (Box 9)
    - Prefeito, Israel Pinheiro 1960 (Box 9)
    - Preteoille 1924 (Box 9)
    - "The Princess" 1909 (Box 9)
    - Quintanilla, Luis 1935, n.d., 2 items (Box 9)
    - Raynor, H.C. 1921 (Box 9)
    - Rieser, Robert 1920 (Box 9)
    - Roberts, George 1922 (Box 9)
    - Robles, Francisco (Coco) and Margara 1940-1965, n.d., 18 items (Box 9)
      with photos and verse
    - Robles, [Margarita] (Miggie) 1943 (Box 9)
    - Roosevelt, George W. 1900, 1906, 2 items (Box 9)
    - Ross, Crystal (Crys) 1923-1957, n.d., 30 items (Box 9)
    - Ruff, Stella (Knobby) 1936, 1947, 2 items (Box 9)
    - Safalgette, L. 1922-1924, 2 items (Box 9)
    - St. John, George C. and Clara 1947, n.d., 2 items (Box 9)
    - Samson, Leon n.d. (Box 9)
    - Savishinsky, Joel 1960 Jun. 2 (Box 9)
    - Saxton, Martha [Mrs. Eugene Saxton] 1947 (Box 9)
    - Saxton, Martha [Mrs. Eugene Saxton] 1943 (Box 9)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur J., Jr. 1958 (Box 9)
    - Schneider, Isidor 1925 (Box 9)
    - Scholle, Hardinge 1916 (Box 9)
    - Schroeder, Peter 1916 (Box 9)
    - Schwartz, H.E. 1936 (Box 9)
    - Seldes, Gilbert 1921-1966, n.d., 9 items (Box 9)
    - Seymour, Charles 1962 (Box 10)
    - Shay, Edie 1941-1958, n.d., 12 items (Box 10)
    - Sheean 1926 (Box 10)
    - Sherk, John L. 1965 (Box 10)
    - Sherrill, Brigadier General Charles H. 1917 (Box 10)
    - Shirley n.d. (Box 10)
    - Shuler, Mrs. C. W. 1947 (Box 10)
      envelope only
    - Shuman, Michael 1940 (Box 10)
    - Silva, Julio 1959-1967, 6 items (Box 10)
    - Simon, Mme. 1954 (Box 10)
      re: Rosenberg case
    - Sinclair, Upton 1932-1938, 3 items (Box 148)
    - Skidmore, Hobert (Skid, Hobie) 1952, n.d., 6 items (Box 10)
    - Skinner[?], B.F. n.d. (Box 10)
    - Smith, Susan 1931-34, n.d., 3 items (Box 10)
    - Soares, Lota de Macedo n.d. (Box 10)
    - Spanos, Nick 1948-1967, n.d., 9 items (Box 10)
    - Sprigg, James P. 1967 (Box 10)
      to: Cousin John
    - Sreny, Paul 1932 (Box 10)
    - Stafford, Martha 1933 (Box 10)
    - Standard American Encyclopedia n.d. (Box 10)
      biographical data by John Dos Passos
    - Standley, Gerald B. 1958 (Box 10)
    - Stefansson, Vilhjalmur 1936 (Box 10)
    - Steloff, Frances 1940 (Box 10)
    - Stephens, Jacqueline 1961 (Box 10)
    - Stephens, Jacqueline 1961 (Box 10)
    - Stolberg, Benjamin 1947 (Box 10)
    - Stolenface, Walter J. 1950 (Box 10)
    - Stout, Mrs. 1944 (Box 10)
    - Stubbs, Kendon 1964 (Box 10)
    - Sugiki, Takeshi 1958 (Box 10)
    - Sult, W.M. 1945 (Box 10)
    - Summers, W. Kay 1920 (Box 10)
    - Swarun, Rama 1964 (Box 10)
      Asia Peoples Anti-Communist League
    - Sweeney, Mrs. Mildred McN. 1919-1924, 17 items (Box 10)
    - Sweeney, Mrs. Mildred McN. 1923-1925, 9 items (Box 10)
    - Sweeney, Mr. and Mrs. Peter 1926, 2 items (Box 10)
    - Swiggett, Howard 1955, 2 items (Box 10)
    - Targ, Mr. 1944 (Box 10)
    - Tameson[?], Storm 1947 (Box 10)
    - Taylor, K.P.A. and Louise M.S. 1936, 2 items (Box 10)
    - Terrell, Clayton 1949, n.d. (Box 10)
      with his TMs, "A Missionary Farm"
    - Thereza, Maria 1968 (Box 10)
    - Thomas, Mary and Felix n.d. (Box 10)
    - Thomas, Norman 1957 (Box 10)
    - Thomas, Norman n.d. (Box 10)
    - Thompson, H. Keith 1963, 2 items (Box 10)
    - Thorne, Maurice A. 1964 (Box 10)
    - Tindall, William 1947 (Box 10)
      re: Edmund Wilson
    - Toiler[?], A. n.d. (Box 10)
      to: "Dear Buddy"
    - Topie 1950 (Box 10)
    - Townsend, Atwood H. n.d. (Box 10)
    - Treat, Ida 1933 (Box 10)
    - Trulock, Camilo 1966 (Box 10)
    - Trilling, Lionel 1947 (Box 10)
    - Tunis, Elizabeth and Edwin 1966-1967, 3 items (Box 10)
    - Tworkov[?], Jack n.d. (Box 10)
    - Unidentified and other miscellaneous correspondance 1900-1963, n.d., 88 items (Box 10)
    - Vanason[?], W. 1905 (Box 10)
      to: "Master Madison"
    - Van den Arend, Hood D. 1922 (Box 10)
    - Van den Arend, Frederick (Van) 1918-1929, n.d., 19 items (Box 10)
    - Van Doren, Mark n.d. (Box 10)
    - Van Nostrand, Albert 1961 (Box 10)
    - Vera, Francisco 1941 (Box 10)
    - Verissimo, Enrico 1959-1970, 18 items (Box 10)
    - Vestry of Cople Parish 1969 (Box 10)
    - Virginia, University Library of 1944, 1961-1961, n.d., 18 items (Box 10)
    - Vittes, Louis 1936 (Box 10)
    - Vlady 1956 (Box 10)
    - Vorse, Mary n.d., 2 items (Box 10)
    - W., Kathrine 1966, n.d., 2 items (Box 11)
    - Waddington, C.H. n.d. (Box 11)
    - Walcott, John 2, 13 items (Box 11)
    - Walker, Charlie R. and Adelaide 1951-1970, n.d., 27 items (Box 11)
    - Ward, William Randolph 1964 (Box 11)
    - Warren, Leslie Frank 1958, 6 items (Box 11)
    - Warren, Leslie Frank 1958, 3 items (Box 11)
    - Watson, Sibley (James) 1917-1918, 2 items (Box 11)
    - Welles, Anna 1912 (Box 11)
    - Werner, M.R. (Morrie) 1967 (Box 11)
    - Werner, Maury R. (Morrie) 1928-1931, n.d., 17 items (Box 11)
    - Wertworth, Shamil[?] 1947 (Box 11)
    - Wescott, Glenway 1941, 1960, 2 items (Box 11)
    - Western Union 1946 (Box 11)
      re: telegram to Dumas Malone
    - Weston, Harold and Faith 1938-1970, n.d., 13 items (Box 11)
    - Weston, Harold and Faith 1937-1970, n.d., 46 items (Box 11)
      with photos; by John Dos Passos
    - Wezschneider, Erni ca. 1957 (Box 11)
    - White, William W. and Connie 1954-1966, n.d., 8 items (Box 11)
    - White, William W. and Connie 1954-1980, n.d. (Box 11)
      by John Dos Passos and family
    - White, Fred Jr. 1940 (Box 11)
    - White, Sallie L. n.d. (Box 11)
      The Emporia Gazette
    - White, William L. 1964-1970, 4 items (Box 11)
    - Who's Who in America 1923 (Box 11)
      biographical entry by John Dos Passos
    - Wilder, Thornton 1941-1942, 2 items (Box 11)
    - Williams, Dickerman C. 1953-1968, 3 items (Box 11)
    - Williams, Roger J. (RJW) 1967 (Box 11)
    - Wilson, Edmund (Bunny) 1932-1970, n.d., 72 items (Box 11)
    - Wilson, James 1940 (Box 11)
    - Wisconsin University Union 1953 (Box 11)
      re: lecture
    - Wood, Grant 1939 (Box 11)
    - Woods, Major General L.E. 1946 (Box 11)
    - Woolcott, Alexander 1941 (Box 11)
    - Wright, Cuthbert n.d., 3 items (Box 11)
    - Zebrock, Stephen 1967 (Box 11)
  - General correspondence between others (Box 11)
    - Baldwin, Mrs. and Wallis Warfield Windsor n.d. (Box 11)
    - Cope, Thomas P. and Aunt Madgie 1919 (Box 11)
    - Foley, Mr. and W. J. Rachow 1924 (Box 11)
    - Frank, Waldo n.d. (Box 11)
    - Gantt, Dr. William Horsley and Takashi Hayashi 1967 (Box 11)
    - Barry, Griffin and C.A. 1919 (Box 11)
    - Fay[?] and Esme and Ken Kramer n.d. (Box 11)
    - Mapes, Mary and George W. Pierson 1965 (Box 11)
    - Murphy, Gerald, and Dawn Powell, Dudley Poore and unidentified 1936-1944, 5 items (Box 11)
    - Norton, Eliot and his brother, Dick 1915, 2 items (Box 11)
    - Powell, Dawn and Pauline Hemingway 1936 (Box 11)
    - Shay, Mr. and Richard Greenleaf 1935 (Box 11)
  - Family correspondence with Dos Passos (Box 12-15)
    - Darneille, H.S. (Aunt Nettie[?]) n.d., 8 items (Box 12)
    - Dos Passos, Cyril F. 1958-1970, 3 items (Box 12)
    - Dos Passos, Katharine Smith (wife) 1928-1945, n.d., 226 items (11 folders) (Box 12)
    - Dos Passos, Katharine Smith (wife) 1930-1945, n.d., 245 items (16 folders) (Box 13)
    - Dos Passos, Louis (half brother) 1940-1958, 9 items (Box 14)
    - Dos Passos, Lucy Addison Sprigg Madison (mother) ca. 1903-1910, n.d., 89 items (Box 14)
    - Dos Passos, Lucy Addison Sprigg Madison (mother) 1904-1912, 76 items (Box 14)
    - Dos Passos, John Randolph Sr. (father) 1901-1917, n.d., ca. 459 items (7 folders) (Box 14-15)
    - Dos Passos, John Randolph Sr. (father) 1911-1912, n.d., 9 items (Box 15)
    - Edward (uncle) 1906 (Box 15)
    - Katherine (cousin) n.d. (Box 15)
    - Madison, James (half brother) 1913-1914, 3 items (Box 15)
    - Pifer, Ida Little (father's cousin) 1921-1945, n.d., 7 items (Box 15)
    - Riely, James (uncle), Aunt Mamie and Lucy Virginia 1918, n.d., 2 items (Box 15)
    - Saran, F.H. (cousin) 1947 (Box 15)
    - Smith, William Benjamin Jr. (brother-in-law) 1920, n.d., 4 items (Box 15)
    - Smith, William Benjamin Sr. (father-in-law) 1934 (Box 15)
    - Smith, Y.K. (brother-in-law) n.d. (Box 15)
    - Sprigg, Lois A. 1918-1919, 2 items (Box 15)
    - Sprigg, Rodney S. 1966 (Box 15)
    - Towne, Gne (uncle) n.d. (Box 15)
    - Unidentified 1901-1904, 2 items (Box 15)
  - Family correspondence between others (Box 16-17)
    - Branham, Mrs. C. (Auntie Millo) to Katharine Dos Passos 1934 (Box 16)
    - Dos Passos, Bessie and Francisca to JRDP, Sr. (their uncle) 1902, 2 items (Box 16)
    - Dos Passos, John R., Sr. to Ida Pifer (his cousin) 1900-1912, n.d., 174 items (5 folders) (Box 16)
    - Dos Passos, John R. Sr. to Lucy S. Madison 1892-1913, n.d., 228 items (9 folders) (Box 17)
    - Madison, James to Lucy S. Madison (his mother) 1885, 1913, 2 items (Box 17)
    - Madison, Lucy S. to John R. Dos Passos Sr. 1909, n.d., 9 items (Box 17)
    - Merrill, Katie to Katharine Dos Passos (her aunt) 1943 (Box 17)
    - Smith, William B. to Katharine Dos Passo (his daughter) and William (his son) 1931 (Box 17)
    - Smith, William B. to Katharine Dos Passos (his sister) 1940 (Box 17)
    - Sprigg, Lucy Addison (John Dos Passos's mother) to her mother and brother 1865 (Box 17)
    - Will to Lucy S. Madison (his sister) 1899 (Box 17)
    - Unidentified 1904, n.d., ca. 30 items (Box 17)
  - Publisher related correspondence with Dos Passos (Box 18-21)
    - American Book Company 1948-1954, 10 items (Box 18)
    - Bass, Basil N. (attorney) 1947-1949, 6 items (Box 18)
    - Bataille, Marie Louise 1949-1950, 7 items (Box 18)
    - Beaufort, Ed, 1947 (Box 18)
    - Boni and Gaer, Inc. 1947-1948, 3 items (Box 18)
    - Brandt and Brandt 1926-1956, ca. 78 items (Box 18)
    - Brandt and Brandt 1929-1957, 2,486 items (11 folders) (Box 18-20)
      "Dos Passos File"
    - Busch, Kurt 1960 (Box 20)
    - Casa Editrice Mondadori 1945-1956, 21 items (Box 20)
    - Constable and Company, Ltd. 1939-1953, n.d., 44 items (Box 20)
    - Curtis Brown, Ltd. 1948-1956, 57 items (Box 20)
    - Dodd, Mead and Company 1953-1955, 4 items (Box 20)
    - Doubleday and Company 1946-1965, 25 items (Box 20)
    - Doubleday, Doran and Company 1941-1945, 16 items (Box 20)
    - Esquire 1948-1951, 10 items (Box 20)
    - Éditions Bernard Grasset 1946-1952, 4items (Box 20)
    - Éditions Du Sagittaire 1948 (Box 20)
    - Editorial Hermes 1956 (Box 20)
    - Franz J. Horch Associates 1926-1972, n.d., ca. 300 items (2 folders) (Box 20)
    - George H. Doran Company 1921 (Box 20)
    - George Routledge and Sons, Ltd. 1943-1949, n.d., 12 items (Box 20)
    - Harcourt, Brace and Company 1941-1942, 8 items (Box 20)
    - Harper and Brothers 1925-1955, 8 items (Box 20)
    - Heath and Company, Ltd., A. M. 1938-1943, 7 items (Box 20)
    - Henry Holt Company n.d. (Box 20)
    - Hills, Mr. 1962-1963, 2 items (Box 20)
    - Houghton Mifflin Company 1942-1975, 137 items (2 folders) (Box 21)
    - Hurst and Blackett 1949 (Box 21)
    - Jacques Chambrun, Inc. 1945-1949, 31 items (Box 21)
    - John Lehmann, Ltd. 1949-1953, 7 items (Box 21)
    - Lawrence Smith Agency 1943-1956, n.d., 27 items (Box 21)
    - Libraire Gaston Gallimard 1945-1951, 6 items (Box 21)
    - Libreria Internacional del Peru 1949, 2 items (Box 21)
    - Life 1945-1951, 6 items (Box 21)
    - Literary Corporation of America 1947, 2 items (Box 21)
    - Miscellaneous 1941-1955, n.d. (Box 21)
    - The Modern Library 1946 (Box 21)
    - The Nation 1924, 2 items (Box 21)
    - NBC 1947-1949, 6 items (Box 21)
    - New Republic 1916 (Box 21)
    - New Statesman and Nation 1932 (Box 21)
    - Peat, Harold R. (lectures agent) 1951-1955, ca. 90 items (Box 21)
    - Permission Requests 1947-1963, n.d., 92 items (Box 21)
    - Pocket Books 1954 (Box 21)
    - Random House 1946-1948, 3 items (Box 21)
    - Reader's Digest 1958-1962, 5 items (Box 21)
    - Robert Hale, Ltd. 1955 (Box 21)
    - Russell, Diamuid 1943 (Box 21)
    - Sadler, Michael 1941-1947, 10 items (Box 21)
    - Selz, George 1946, n.d., 8 items (Box 21)
    - Simon and Schuster 1932-1951, 3 items (Box 21)
    - Spanos, Nick 1950-1961, n.d., 10 items (Box 21)
    - Story and The Story Press 1947-1950, 4 items (Box 21)
    - Time 1947-1952, 10 items (Box 21)
    - William H. Wise and Company 1940-1951, 3 items (Box 21)
    - Williams, C. Dickerson (attorney) 1957-1960, 4 items (Box 21)
  Series II
- Writings (manuscripts, speeches and research)
  - Published works on society, politics, history and travel (Box 22-109)
    - Adventures of a Young Man (1939) 1931-ca. 1939 (Box 22-23)
      Manuscript draft, ca. 1939 (4 folders) Background data, 1931 Publisher's setting copy, ca. 1939
    - Airways, Inc (1928) 1925-1929, n.d. (Box 23)
      Manuscript draft, Act III, n.d. Author's text emendations, 1925-1929 (also includes The Garbage Man text
    - The Best Times (1966) ca. 1965-1968 (Box 24-26)
      Notes and outlines, ca. 1965-1966 Early manuscript drafts, ca. 1965-1966 (7 folders) Final manuscript drafts, ca. 1965-1966 (6 folders) Reviews, 1966-1968
    - The Big Money (1936) ca. 1932-1956[?], n.d. (Box 26-29)
      Notes and outlines, ca. 1932-1936 (3 folders) Early manuscript drafts, ca. 1932-1936 (4 folders) Publisher's setting copy, ca. 1932-1936 (4 folders) Later revisions, TV adaptation and correspondence, ca. 1932-1956[?], n.d.
    - Brazil on the Move (1963) 1945-1964, n.d. (Box 30-33)
      Notes and outlines, 1959-1963 (3 folders) Manuscript drafts, ca. 1962-1963 (6 folders) Publisher's setting copy and galleys, 1963 (2 folders) Background data and photos (5 folders) Portuguese books on Brazil, 1945-1961, n.d. (8 folders) Reviews, 1963-1964
    - Century's Ebb: The Thirteenth Chronicle (1975) 1959-1970, n.d. (Box 34-41)
      Notes and outlines, Parts I-V, n.d. (2 folders) Miscellaneous notes, n.d. (2 folders) Manuscript drafts, Part I, n.d. (8 folders) Manuscript drafts, Part II, n.d. (11 folders) Manuscript drafts, Part III, n.d. (6 folders) Manuscript drafts, Part IV, n.d. (5 folders) Manuscript drafts, Part V, n.d. (7 folders) Manuscript drafts not used in final version, n.d. Printer's master copy, 1975 (9 folders) TMs, final version, 1975 (8 folders) Research, Parts II, III, V and miscellaneous, 1959-1970, n.d. (5 folders) Related correspondence, 1967-1969, 8 items
    - Chosen Country (1951) 1949-1950, 1952, n.d. (Box 41-45)
      Notes and outlines, 1949-1950 Early manuscript drafts, 1949-1950 (8 folders) Later manuscript drafts, 1949-1950 (5 folders) Publisher's setting copy, 1949-1950 (4 folders) TMs, final version, 1949-1950 (4 folders) Print copies: Omnibook abridgement and Chapter 7 fragment, 1952, n.d.
    - Easter Island: Island of Enigmas (1971) ca. 1970-1971, n.d. (Box 46-47)
      Manuscript drafts, n.d. (5 folders) Galleys, proofs and photographs, ca. 1970-1971 (4 folders) Research and background data, 1970, n.d. (2 folders) Related correspondence, 1970
    - Facing the Chair (1927) n.d. (Box 48)
      Early manuscript drafts, 1920s Newsclip, John Dos Passos letter to Harvard president, Lawrence Lowell, 8 Aug. 1927
    - The 42nd Parallel (1930) ca. 1930, ca. 1956, 1964 (Box 48)
      Notes, ca. 1930 Early manuscript drafts, ca. 1930 (2 folders) Later reworked manuscript drafts, ca. 1956, ca. 1956 Print copy text excerpts, ca. 1930 Correspondence re: Czech edition, 1964 Reviews, 1930
    - The Garbage Man (1926) ca. 1925-1929 (Box 48)
      Early manuscript draft, ca. 1925 Author's text emendations, 1925-1929
    - The Grand Design (1949) 1945-1949, n.d. (Box 49-50)
      Notes and outlines, 1945-1949, n.d. (3 folders) Early manuscript drafts, 1945-1949 (3 folders) Later manuscript drafts, 1945-1949 (4 folders) Publisher's setting copy, 1949 (2 folders) Background data, 1949
    - The Great Days (1958) ca. 1956-1958 (Box 51-52)
      Notes, ca. 1956-1958 Early manuscript drafts, ca. 1956-1958 (3 folders) Later manuscript drafts, ca. 1956-1958 Final manuscript drafts, ca. 1956-1958 (3 folders) TMs, final version, ca. 1956-1958
    - The Ground We Stand On (1941) ca. 1941-1942 (Box 53-54)
      Notes, ca. 1941 Manuscript drafts, Parts I-III, ca. 1941 (7 folders) Publisher's setting copy, ca. 1941 (3 folders) Book's dust jacket, ca. 1941 Reviews, 1941-1942
    - The Head and Heart of Thomas Jefferson (1954) 1941-1954, n.d. (Box 55-57)
      Early manuscript drafts, 1944-1954 (8 folders) Later manuscript drafts, 1944-1954 (6 folders) Publisher's setting copy, 1944-1954 (4 folders) Background research and miscellaneous, 1941-1954, n.d. (3 folders) Reviews, 1954
    - In All Countries (1934) 1927-1929, 1934-1935, n.d. (Box 58)
      Notes, manuscript drafts, proofs, and reworked articles, 1927-1929, n.d. Reviews, 1934-1935
    - Journeys Between Wars (1938) 1938-1939, n.d. (Box 58)
      Notes, n.d. Manuscript drafts, n.d. (2 folders) Reviews, 1938-1939
    - Manhattan Transfer (1925) ca. 1920s, 1960, n.d. (Box 58-59)
      Notes, ca. 1920s Early manuscript drafts, ca. 1924 Later manuscript drafts, ca. 1925 (3 folders) Manuscript draft of "Introduction" text to Portuguese translation, 1960 Review (by D.H. Lawrence), n.d.
    - The Men Who Made the Nation (1957) 1955-1956, ca. 1957 (Box 59-64)
      Notes and outlines, ca. 1957 (6 folders) Early manuscript drafts, ca. 1957 (12 folders) Later manuscript drafts, ca. 1957 (10 folders) Related correspondence, 1955-1956
    - Midcentury (1961) 1954-1958, ca. 1960-1964, n.d. (Box 64-69)
      Notes and outlines, ca. 1960-1963 (2 folders) Early manuscript drafts, ca. 1960 (7 folders) Later manuscript drafts, ca. 1960 (3 folders) TMs, final version, ca. 1960 (4 folders) Publisher's setting copy, ca. 1960 (4 folders) Galleys, proofs and print excerpts, 1960 (3 folders) Background and related correspondence, 1954-1958, n.d. (4 folders) Reviews, 1960-1964
    - Mr. Wilson's War (1962) ca. 1961-1963, n.d. (Box 70-76)
      Notes and outlines, n.d (8 folders) Early manuscript drafts, ca. 1961-1962 (12 folders) Later manuscript drafts, ca. 1961-1962 TMs, final version, 1962 (11 folders) Publisher's setting copy, 1962 (7 folders) Source notes and related correspondence, 1961-1962, n.d. Reviews, 1962-1963
    - Most Likely to Succeed (1954) ca. 1954, n.d. (Box 77-78)
      Manuscript notes, ca. 1954 Early manuscript drafts, ca. 1954 (5 folders) Later manuscript drafts, ca. 1954 Final manuscript drafts, ca. 1954 (2 folders) Reviews, n.d.
    - Nineteen Nineteen (1932) ca. 1932 (Box 79)
      Manuscript drafts, ca. 1932 (4 folders) Miscellaneous print copy excerpts, ca. 1932
    - Number One (1943) ca. 1943-1948, n.d. (Box 79-80)
      Early manuscript drafts, ca. 1943-1948 (3 folders) TMs, theater version, 1948 TMs with autograph changes used as prize in WW-II Bond campaign, n.d.
    - Occasions and Protests (1964) n.d. (Box 80-81)